hello friends welcome to my channel
today we will be discussing about icic
lombard
general insurance company so let's get
started
before that there is a disclaimer so
this video is intended only for
educational purposes
the facts and figures which i have
mentioned in this video they are also
publicly available
and i am not liable for any quality
accuracy completeness
timeliness of the information provided
for any direct indirect consequential
incidental or any kind of damages which
may arise
out of use of the information which is
presented in this video
uh please do your own due diligence and
consult your financial advisor
before making an investment uh these are
all my personal
opinions uh based on the facts and
figures which are publicly available
i do own the stock in my personal
portfolio please watch the video till
the end
so that you don't miss out on any key
metric
and the opinions around that
so i say lombard general insurance
company basically
uh the business is general insurance
which is different than
non-life so it's a non-life insurance uh
basically it's not a
they also have isis they also have a icc
potential
life which deals with life insurance so
this is the
uh non-life insurance company it got
listed on
stock exchanges both on bomb stock
exchange and national stock exchange in
year 2017.
it's not uh it's quite recent listing
and it is the largest private sector
non-life insurer in india
based on the gross direct premium income
uh
from in the fiscal 2020. so it is
promoted by icc bank
and they hold around 51.88
this company has very high institutional
holding
so mutual funds uh fbi's fias
they all hold this they are having a
holding in this company
to the extent of 41.04 percent
and a small portion is held by retail
investors and non-institutions which is
around
7.08 percent a very low uh float
and uh not a very high ownership in
terms of retail investors
and what it offers is it offers
comprehensive and well diversified
range of insurance products which
includes your fire insurance
motor vehicle insurance health insurance
travel and personal accident covers
marine insurance
and all of that it serves individuals
also
corporate large corporate houses and
also government customers
and they have a variety of distribution
channels
offline and online so
let's see about some key stock facts so
the market cup of this company is around
64 277 crore
uh it's trading at around 14 14 rupees
and the high which this stock has made
is around 1626
and the low is 11.25
the price to earning ratio is around
43.64
and price to book is slightly expensive
8.65
dividend yield is not very high it's
around point two eight percent only
but uh but ross is good twenty eight
point eight percent
return on capital employed return on
equity is around twenty one point six
percent and the face value of this stock
uh is around
10 rupees so all of these figures are uh
as of
30th april 2021.
coming to the key strengths of this
company so
there are there are around you know i
can broadly say
there are five key areas where they have
definitely key strengths
so one of one of them is they they are
market leadership they are able to
maintain the market
leadership position across all the
segments in which they are operating
including
uh you know motor insurance health fire
engineering liability in marine segments
over many years now they continuously
innovate products
and solutions to suit their evolving
customer needs so they have a
diverse product range and they promote
them through
multiple channel distribution okay uh
they also serve customers by leveraging
digital technologies
like artificial intelligence ai based
machine learning analytics they do a lot
of
analytics they also do iots
and then they they are able to reduce
decision making steps in their workflows
so which means that
they are able to have a very good
turnaround time
uh to and that really improves their
operating efficiencies so they have done
really excellent excellent
in the terms of customer service by
implementation of
latest technologies they also have very
good good
risk management practices they have a
data driven risk selection framework and
they they also they also invest
very high investments in debt portfolio
sovereign securities and most of these
securities are aa rated
which are which are in bonds and
debentures which gives them
a better risk management so they have
good very good
risk management practices also they also
uh they also do capital conservation
they don't
spend or they don't invest
you know at a very aggressive pace so
they
they they are conservative as such and
they also have a reinsurance done
quality reinsurance done and they have
practices
uh in in the risk management and capital
conservation
there are many key differentiators also
in this company
with compared to any other non-life
insurance company
so it is having a very bra strong brand
equity so which means that
if you can see the gross return premium
is around 135.92 billion rupees
very high they have issued over 26.2
million policies and settled 1.8 million
claims
which is a really big number so they
have a very strong brand equity and
operations
across uh across locations they have
very good
distribution network around 273 branches
840 virtual offices
they have a partnership with the garages
they have a network of around
8 800 garages and they have a
network of around 6536 hospitals tie-ups
they have a diversified product mix like
you know motor health
travel personal accident fire marine and
others all of these segments
they have very comprehensive product
portfolio they
they are enabled by technology so they
have a very good technology
differentiation
and they have digital services
capabilities which they are continuously
improving
in the last several years so
95.6 percent of their policies are
issued electronically
they have 31 cashless authorization
done through implementation of
artificial intelligence
they they have mobile applications
through which a lot of claims comes
through
they also have they have enabled
applications they have enabled websites
they have enabled work from home for
their employees to the tune of around
9000 employees
they can work from home all of these
figures are
as per the annual reports what they
published
and it is publicly available they have
very good risk management
services as i also mentioned earlier in
the earlier slide
they have a predictive loss modeling
framework which reduces the
risk when they select select
the case for the for the premium and for
providing the policies
they have a very diversified exposure
they have a reinsurance done
and they also have a zero incidence of
in debt portfolio since they have
started a business since inception
these are very good key differentiators
when you compare this company with any
other company which is
listed let's see the financial
performance so financial performance
so they have a combined ratio so this
ratio is basically should
should be lesser the better that's why
this needs an improvement so what it
means is
that the outflow
compared to the incoming premiums is
more
the kind of claims they are processing
they are more a bit
compared to what they're getting as a
premium so it's a combined ratio
i think this is what uh it needs a bit
of improvement should be lesser than 100
uh return on average equity is good uh
compared to
if you compare it to year on year there
is a improvement
uh there is a increase and when you
compare quarter to quarter
from the last year it's flat
profit before tax has improved on both
the year to year comparison and the
quarter to quarter
and uh profit after tax has also
gone up from uh and all of these figures
are in billion rupees
so it has you know you can see the
increase between you know profit after
tax is around
23.4 percent increased year-on-year
and profit before tax uh has increased
to around 15.1 percent year-on-year
quarter on quarter also if you see the
there is increase of
uh profit after tax is around 22.6
percent
and there is increase of 21.4 percent
quarter to quarter for the profit before
tax all of these
numbers are reflecting good uh on the
financial performance
the only thing is the combined ratio
should should improve so they should
they need some
strategy around improving this combined
ratio
financial performance if we see for the
past years
you can see the sales growth so over the
10 years they have grown by
50 by 16 percent around 5 years 15
percent compounded and 3 years is around
21 percent compounded so that is a good
growth in the sales if you see the
profit growth that is also pretty decent
uh very good numbers 10 years it is
around 25 percent five years 24
and three last three years is around 36
percent
uh and then the stock price cagr is
available only for
three years and one year because it got
listed in 2012 only
so last three years it's around 23 stock
price
has uh uh increased and around one year
it is almost like
it has not done much um so the
the valuation looks reasonable at this
point of time
return on equity is also good uh
last 10 years average if you see the
return on equity it is under 18
5 years 20 percent and last three years
is around 21 percent
uh good figures now so let's see the
pros and cons
the pros in his company is almost
debt-free there is
no very little debt it has delivered a
very good profit growth
of twenty three point seven five uh chr
over
last five years and uh
it is has been maintaining healthy
dividend payout of around seventeen
point two two percent
these are the pros cons are it is
trading at eight point four six times
the book value which is
slightly expensive uh and then there is
earnings include there's other income
they have included 495.5 to crore
uh that is that also just increases the
earnings but that is the exceptional
item
uh it's another income and promoter
holding has slightly decreased
over the last three years uh so they
have reduced i think around
four four point zero four percent so
these are the only things which
which i could figure out uh which they
have there are some
pros and cons associated with the stock
then what are the growth opportunities
so general insurance industry if you see
uh this is a highly underpenetrated so
if
it is only 0.97 percent of gdp
whereas the global average is around
2.78
and this is in spite of uh
the industry which is growing at sixteen
point seven at a as i see this is a cagr
uh compounded annual growth rate since
2001.
so there is a lot of scope of
of catching up uh i i think there is
excellent growth opportunity in this
sector private sector accounts for 48.2
percent of the market share and icc
lombard is the market leader in that
and they have a market share of around
12.6 among
private players which are listed or
unlisted and seven percent in the
industry
the overall uh non-life
insurance industry general insurance uh
they have this uh market share there are
significant growth of prospects given
the country's
favorable demographic uh especially in
the health insurance sector
there is a big growth which is which is
due
and as the time goes by this is going to
do very well
the regulator irdi also continues to
introduce regulatory changes
and you know they are trying to enhance
the market context
they are rolling out a different kind of
guidelines too
to so that the there is a welfare for
the customers
they are bringing in a lot of
regulations good practices
industry trends are being set so that
will really help
going forward this sector is going to
get re-rated
when when foreign players continue to
increase stakes in indian companies
partner companies there are regulatory
changes which will happen
and then there is affordability also to
buy insurance
as the people become more aware and the
product evolves
over a period of time this has potential
to give multi-fold returns
over next many many years but they i
think
there is a lot of growth opportunities
in general insurance sector
and icc lombard being a market leader
is definitely going to do well if they
continue their market share and if
they continue to gain also the market
share
they will really make their market cap
will increase over period of time
and they will grow so what should be
done
so if you have already invested into the
stock then probably
uh you can you can hold on hold it on to
that
do not sell it keep around four to six
percent
in your portfolio the location should be
around this percentage
uh by on major declines when whenever
there is a bad news
or not so good results expected by the
street and the stock falls
you know ten to fifteen percent or five
to ten percent that point of time
you can buy that uh and then or you can
also do a sip
for some time till you reach the your uh
desired portfolio at a location uh
current market
uh evaluation looks reasonable uh
if the market declines from here at
around
five to ten percent whenever it happens
that is the definitely a good time
to accumulate this stock it's going to
be a long term play it is not for
traders
it is not for buying today and selling
tomorrow you need to stick to that
and give it time so that the company
grows
with the opportunities which are being
played out
over the period of time thanks for
uh watching the video uh please
do like and subscribe so that whenever i
create
videos like this next time you will get
a notification
thanks a lot